Today is a very important day in our lives as Sahaja yogis.
今日はサハジャヨギとしての 人生でとても大切な日です
This is the day when Sahasrara was opened out,
サハスララが開いた日です
which was really a very charismatic thing that happened.
真にカリスマティックなことが起こりました
I never expected
私の生きている間に出来るとは
that in My lifetime I’ll be able to work it out,
思っていませんでしたが
but it has been,
できました
and so many of you have got your Sahasrara opened.
そして皆の多くのサハスララが開きました
Without that you could never have known
それなしでは真理を知ることは
what is the truth.
できなかったでしょう
You were all lost, as everybody is.
皆同じように人生に迷っていました
First of all,
第一に
Sahasrara is the only way we can perceive,
サハスララ以外に現実を知り
understand and know the reality.
理解する道はありません
You have come to know
あなたは現実とは何か
as to what is the reality,
悟りました
and you are enjoying that state
そして現実を知っている意識を
where you know what is the reality.
楽しんでいます
It’s a great blessing that Sahasrara was opened out
サハスララが開いてそれを知ったのは
and all of you got your realization.
大きな恩恵です
Otherwise all talks are just talks
でなければそれはただの話にすぎす
– has no meaning,
意味がありませんし
has no understanding;
理解もありません
and that’s why My first anxiety was to open Sahasrara.
だからまずサハスララを開きたかったのです
That worked out,
それができました
worked out well,
上手く行きました
and all of you have got
それで皆さんの
your Sahasrara opened.
サハスララが開きました
It’s a remarkable thing.
特別なことです
Nobody can believe that so many of you have got
こんな多くのサハスララが開くとは
your Sahasrara open, but I can see now clearly
誰も信じられないことですが
the light on top of your heads.
私には皆の頭上にハッキリと 光が見えます
Whatever you have achieved is remarkable, no doubt.
間違いなく素晴らしいことです
It is because of honest searching,
誠実な探求のおかげです
honest searching,
誠実に探求したから
that you have got it.
得られたのです
My doing is nothing,
私は何もしていません
because you were just there
そこにたまたまあなたがいて
like a lamp and I just enlightened it, that’s all.
ランプを灯すようにしただけです
It’s not such a big thing to do,
大したことではありません
as you people have achieved your state,
あなたがその意識に至ったのです
state of enlightenment,
悟りの意識です
that you got it because
それを求め
you were hankering after it,
作用させ
working it out,
努力をしたから
and you did it.
得られたのです
It’s very creditable.
立派なことです
Credit doesn’t go to Me, I think,
私の手柄ではないと思います
because I had a open Sahasrara,
私はサハスララを開いたけれど
but to achieve that in you people
それをあなたが体得していくのが
was so joy-giving for Me.
私にはとても嬉しい
Now you will understand,
だからあなたは理解できます
because if Sahasrara is not open you can’t talk people,
サハスララが開くまでは 話せません
you can’t say anything to them
何も通じません
– it’s just they don’t understand.
わからないからです
With the Sahasrara open your understanding improves so much.
サハスララが開くことで 理解が大きく進みます
That is what has happened with all of you,
それが皆に起こりました
and I’m so very happy
だから嬉しいです
that it’s so many people there are sitting here
多くの人がここに座り
who have got their Sahasraras open.
サハスララを開きました
And there are many who have not come.
更にに来ていない人も多くいます
So it’s a big achievement for human beings
つまりこれは人類にとって大きなことで
to get it so much collectively
集団でサハスララが
Sahasrara opened,
開きました
by which you know the truth,
それによって初めて
absolute truth.
究極の真理がわかります
Whatever you know after your realization
リアリゼーションの後に知ることは
is the absolute truth.
何であれ究極の真理です
You don’t argue then,
それを議論したり
don’t question,
疑いません
you just know it and you accept it
それを知って受け入れます
as a knowledge.
知識としてです
It’s such a nice thing that it was all there,
全てがあったのは良かったけれど
but it was not open.
開いていませんでした
And when it opened out, how people have understood Me
それが開けば私のことが解る
and also the laws of the Divine.
それも聖なる法則です
It’s such a blessing of the Divine
サハスララが開いたのは
that you have got your Sahasrara opened out,
偉大な神の恵みですが
for which you may say, “We didn’t do anything, Mother.”
何もしていないと言うかもしれないけど
It’s not so.
違います
Your search for truth
あなたの真理の探求が
was intense and definite.
真摯でありはっきりしていたから
You wanted to know the truth,
真理を知りたいと望んだから
that’s why it has worked out.
それが叶ったのです
Otherwise no amount of money,
でなければどんなお金も
no amount of effort,
多大な努力も
nothing would have helped.
何も上手く行かなかったでしょう
Sahasrara had to open by itself.
サハスララは自分で開く必要があります
It’s all your building up, I should say,
あなたの準備ができていたから
it’s all your doing to yourself
すべてあなたが自分でしたことです
that has brought forth such a beautiful happening.
それによって美しい事が起きましたが
I do not take any credit for that at all.
私の手柄ではありません
Definitely I must say
ハッキリ言います
that I have made you understand
私が教えたように
that it’s important that your Sahasrara should be opened.
サハスララが開くのが大切です
No more arguments,
それ以上話すこともなく
no more suggestions,
質問もありませｎ
nothing, but have your own Sahasrara open,
サハスララを開くことによってのみ
which tells you what is the truth is.
何が真理か分かります
In these beautiful circumstances,
この美しい状況で
what could your Mother say?
母として何が言えるでしょう
I can only say that continue to live a life of reality,
現実を理解して行きなさいと
of understanding.
それだけです
In everything you will find
全てにおいて
there is truth,
真理がありますが
and how do we use that truth is our own achievement.
どうやって成就した真理を使えるでしょう
People are lost
人々は迷っています
because they have no knowledge.
知識がないからです
Knowledge from the books is no knowledge.
本からの知識は本物ではありません
Their knowledge must come from within,
知識は内面から来るものです
from within themselves, you see,
自分たちの中からです
and that has happened because of Sahasrara opening.
サハスララが開いたからできるのです
In all the countries it has happened,
どの国でもそれができています
and it will be in the whole world,
世界中で起こるでしょう
so many people will get realization.
多くの人が悟るでしょう
But only thing I feel that you people should have
ただあなた達に一つだけ言いたいのは
no emotional attachment to it,
感情的に執着しないことです
not emotional but realistic attachment,
現実的につながるのです
that it is there, it has happened, it’s working out.
そこにあって それが起こり 働きます
Then you will be able to give realizations to other,
すると人々に悟りを与えられます
you’ll understand the importance of realization.
リアリゼーションの大切さが分かるでしょう
Unless and until you use it
使わないと
you won’t know what is the power of realization is.
リアリゼーションの力が分かりまsん
So you must learn how to use this power
なのでこの力の使い方を覚えなさい
which is within you,
あなたの中にあります
which has started working out,
それは作用し始めました
and which will give you such a immense capacity.
それは莫大な能力を与えるでしょう
My health is little bit gone down – after all, I am very old.
歳なので　私の体調は少し落ちました
But still I don’t feel tired in any way
でも疲れは感じません
while addressing you;
皆さんに話していて
I feel so enamored
夢中になってしまいます
that there are so many Sahaja yogis,
沢山のサハジャヨギがいて
so many whose Sahasrara is opened,
沢山のサハスララが開き
and they’re enjoying their Sahasrara.
皆がそれを愉しんでいます
Actually I would have liked you to ask Me questions,
実は質問を受けたいと思っています
but you can write questions and send Me written ones.
質問をかいて送ってください
Then I’ll try to answer them some time.
のちにお答えしましょう
Will be a much better idea.
それが良いでしょう
So thank you very much.
ありがとうございます
May God bless you.
神の恩恵がありますように
Grow into Sahaj,
サハジャに育っていきなさい
grow into your being.
自分になっていきなさい
May God bless you, all My blessings.
神の恩恵を 私の恩恵を授けます